I live at No. 15
我家住在
Anren Lane on the west side
高昌庙镇西边
of Gaochang Temple Town.
安仁弄十五号
[Hurry up or I'll dock your pay!]
再磨蹭扣你工钱了
Coming!
好 来了
Make sure you come, okay?
那个 你千万要来啊
[No. 15 Anren Lane,]
高昌庙镇西边
west side of Gaochang Temple Town.
安仁弄十五号
Move it!
快点儿
Got it!
好嘞
The spot where you're standing
你们现在所站的地方
is the
是已经有
first industrial factory,
近七十年历史的
nearly 70 years old.
工业第一厂
This is where our first machine tools,
中国第一批机床
the first furnace of steel,
第一炉钢
as well as smokeless powder,
以及无烟火药
rifles, steel cannons, and ironclad ships
步枪 钢炮 铁甲炮舰
originated!
都始出于此
This is
这里是
where the dream of our maritime power began.
中国海洋梦开始的地方
We will spend
这一周的时间
the week here.
我们都要待在这儿
[Unpack your bags.]
放好行李
[You have five minutes]
给你们五分钟的时间
[before heading]
一起到码头
[to the dock to take a look.]
去熟悉下情况
Yes, sir!
是
Is that Yuansheng over there?
你们看那是远生吗
Yuansheng!
远生
It's really him!
真是远生
Long time no see.
好久不见
It's been
可不吗
over two months.
这都两个多月没见了
Looking even sharper in that outfit.
这身打扮更有卖相了
How's the battleship handling?
你那军舰开得怎么样
Let's not talk here.
别 别在这边
We can chat as we walk.
咱边走边说
Let's go.
走走走
Hey, listen,
臭小子我告诉你啊
you can't just call him that.
以后不能乱叫了
It's Mr. Hua now.
得叫华公子
No, he is Yuansheng.
我就叫远生
Alright, alright.
行行行
Dongbao!
冬宝
come out here!
冬宝快出来
[Coming!]
来了哥
I've told you not
都说了别拿那么多东西
to bring so much stuff.
又拿这么多
Chief.
所长
Yuansheng.
向警官
Don't know her, right?
不认识吧
Dongbao's wife.
冬宝媳妇 小玉
He's from the Fourth Station...
这是我们四所原来的
How about Yuansheng like before?
还是叫向警官吧 别扭
Hello, Yuansheng.
向警官好
Hello.
你好
Go inside.
走走走
Come on.
别愣着 快进
I brought some fruit.
买了点水果
Oh,
我来吧
thanks.
谢谢
Dongbao, here!
冬宝 快
Coming!
来
Yu, pour some tea!
小玉倒点茶啊
Here.
拿着这个
Wait.
来 哥等会儿
3, 2, 1, go!
一二三 走
How is it here?
看看 怎么样
This young couple
这小两口日子过的是
is living a good life.
红红火火
[Mr. Zuo, Help yourself.]
所长你们找地方坐
When did they get married?
冬宝什么时候结的婚
After leaving the police,
冬宝离开四所以后
Dongbao went to the dock.
不是去了码头了吗
Just then, this girl
正好碰上这姑娘
was about to jump into the river
被人逼债
because of debts.
差点儿跳江
Dongbao saved her.
冬宝把她给救了
It was love at first sight.
一见钟情
And now they're living together.
过上小日子了 你说
Here's some water.
所长 向警官 喝水
Alright. Don't fuss.
好 别忙活了
Careful, it's hot.
小心烫啊
C'mon, everyone's busy.
别喝了 都忙着呢
The water can wait.
你一会儿再喝吧
Always bossing me around.
臭小子就知道指使我
[Anything else?]
还有啥东西
[Coal and stuff everywhere.]
有的是 煤球什么的
[Lend me a hand!]
都搭把手啊
Dongbao, I put it
冬宝给你放这儿了啊
on that table.
放那桌子上
[See,]
哥你看
we
那里边
haven't finished the rice
还有你上次拿的那米
you brought here last time.
都没吃完呢
[It has long life.]
这东西不容易坏
[Just keep it for later.]
留着慢慢吃呗
[It's colder. They'll come in handy.]
最近变天 用得着
[But that's too much.]
那你这也太多了哥
[We're family.]
一家人我告诉你啊
[Feel free to say anything you need.]
以后缺啥少啥你就说
[We'll bring it over.]
我们就给你送来 好吧
[Thanks.]
谢谢所长
[You haven't]
让你干点儿活
[finished your work yet.]
都没干完呢
[I'm not getting any younger.]
我多大你多大
[Just some spinach...]
拿两个菠菜你就
[Don't start acting like Erbai
别跟二白学
[ordering me around.]
还指使我呢
[Do some work...]
你干干活吧你
[You've brought so much.]
你们拿的东西真不少
[Don't do this next time.]
下次可不能这样了
Dongbao!
冬宝
[Yes?]
哥
Water boiling.
快 水开了
Coming.
好了
Today, we've got plenty of meat.
来 今天咱肉管够啊
Good.
行
Don't hold back.
可劲儿吃
Yuansheng,
远生
how long will you stay this time?
这次回来准备待几天
About a week.
一周左右
We need to obtain
学校过来接收
some new torpedo boats.
一批新的鱼雷艇
That's beyond us.
我们也听不懂
Did Dongbao
对了
tell you what's happening
冬宝跟你说
at the Fourth Station?
四所的事儿了吗
He did.
说了
Are you planning
那你们还打算
to continue as policemen?
继续当警察吗
Dongbao is considering it.
现在冬宝有这个打算
He's been
他现在是
working at the docks
一边在码头搬货挣钱
and applied
一边
for reinstatement.
往上面交了留用申请
It's been over a month.
这都快一个多月了吧
Just about right.
差不多了哥
We cannot predict the result.
咱也不知道能不能通过
I just
我主要是
can't part with the uniform.
有点儿舍不得那身衣服
Even a registry
我留着那身衣服
or traffic cop
他要是让我
is enough
当什么户籍警 交通警
to make me happy.
我都愿意
Dongbao is persistent.
冬宝就是执着
Yuansheng,
远生我给你介绍一下
I'm gonna tell you our jobs.
我们几个人工作啊
You wouldn't believe it.
你都想不到
I'm now a taxi driver.
我现在是出租车司机
You know that.
这 这你知道
Hongfa's restaurant
鸿发家酒楼生意
wasn't doing well.
不太景气
It's closed.
就关门了
He's working at a mall
那现在也挺好
as a salesperson.
在商场当售货员
Our director
所长
is serving food
调十六铺分局
at the canteen of Shiliupu.
食堂给人发饭
Yes,
是
it's good.
挺好的
Like retirement.
在那儿养老
What about Chen Hao?
陈浩呢
I don't know.
我不知道
We don't see him much.
也不见我们
I don't care.
爱干什么干什么
Watch your tone.
怎么说话
He is doing well,
那臭小子也挺好的
just like me,
和我一样
at Shiliupu.
在十六铺分局
He's in the Criminal
不过我是在食堂打饭
Investigation Dept.
他在刑警科
Under Feng Guangyun?
他去了冯广云的刑警科
Unbelievable, right?
谁能想到
Despite the unhappy past,
当初那么得罪那冯广云
he was left behind by Feng.
这冯科长还愿意收留他
And
他呢
he is
也愿意跟人
willing to do so.
屁股后面忙活
He
这小子
is smarter
比我想象中
than I thought.
要聪明得多
It's all because he made his mark
还不是因为孟家的案子
with the murder case.
他立功了吗
What you're saying...
你看你这
is not wrong.
话说得也没错
Since he handed over
他不把那个凶手
the killer to the Concession,
交到租界了吗
the female inspector
那女督察员啊
put in a good word for him.
一高兴说了好话
It actually worked.
结果关键时候管用了
Then he's got promoted.
高升了 刑警科了
Otherwise, he'd guard at the
要不然我在食堂打饭
entrance
他得
while I serve the meal.
他到门口看大门得
That's all for him.
不说他 不说他了
But
那个
why hasn't Minmin arrived yet?
珉敏怎么还没来啊
[She's still at the training class.]
珉敏姐还在训练班
I left her a note.
我给她留字条了
She should be here soon.
快过来了吧应该
[There's no rush.]
等会儿 不着急
[Let's wait then.]
那再等等
[Anyone want coriander?]
这有香菜谁要
I do.
我要
It's so cold out there.
冷死我了 好冷
Speak of the devil!
说曹操曹操到
I tried to learn driving today
我今天去学车又没学会
and almost got kicked out.
差点儿被赶出来
[I just saw a jeep parked]
我刚看见弄堂门口
[at the alley entrance.]
停了辆吉普车
[Whose is that?]
那是谁的呀
[If I had a car like that,]
我要是有那么辆车
I'd practice every day.
我就天天练
Literally...
天天练我就
[Surprise!]
惊不惊喜 意不意外
Yuansheng is back!
向警官又回来了
Long time no see.
好久不见
When did you get back?
你什么时候回的上海
Just arrived today.
今天刚到
[Have a sit.]
不是 这
[We've been waiting for you!]
别傻站着了 就等你呢
[Come on!]
快来 坐下
[Come,]
快
[hurry up.]
坐坐坐
[Sit by the stove.]
坐火炉边上 暖暖
[Warm you up.]
坐火堆儿旁边 暖和
[Alright,]
行了
[everyone's here.]
人都到齐了咱就开吃吧
[Let's do it!]
来吧
[Everyone, dig in!]
来 都动筷
[Have a drink.]
来 先喝一个
Yu,
小玉
rice balls for you.
这是给你带的粢饭团
I remember you love it.
上回你说爱吃
[Thank you.]
谢谢珉敏姐
[Minmin,]
珉敏
Yuansheng
向警官这次
came back
是跟着学校部队
with the school fleet,
一起回来的
[heading to Nanjing on a boat.]
要开船回南京
[That's a warship.]
那叫军舰
[Right,]
好
[warship.]
对 军舰
[Poor memory.]
我又忘了
I heard
我听他们说
you wanna reapply for the police.
你打算重新考警察
And you?
你呢
How long will you stay?
你在上海待多久
About a week.
一周左右
It's my first time
我还是
seeing you in uniform.
第一次看你穿军装
You look pretty sharp.
确实蛮帅气的
Thanks.
谢谢
[C'mon,]
行了 你俩别聊了
[have some meat.]
肉都熟了
Eat first, chat later.
吃完肉一会儿聊
[Right!]
来
[Why the rush? Wait!]
这么着急 等会儿
Let's drink together!
来 先端一个
Here!
来
Cheers!
干一个啊
[It's rare for us to get together!]
难得聚这么齐啊
I'm starving.
饿死我了
Come on, eat up!
来 快吃
[Minmin,]
快吃珉敏
[have some more meat.]
多吃点儿肉啊
[Finished already?]
又干了啊
[Pour him less.]
你少给他倒点儿
[Why do you drink so fast?]
你老喝那么快干什么
It's so good.
好吃
[I grew it myself.]
是吧 都是我自己种的
[Eat up.]
快吃
[Have more meat.]
多吃点儿肉 珉敏
[Alright.]
好
[Empty again?]
又干了啊
[Where's my meat?]
肉呢
[I just put it down!]
我下的肉呢
[Chen Hao.]
陈浩
Captain Wang.
王队长
Take minutes of meeting for today.
今天会议写个记录
When do you need it?
什么时候要
First thing tomorrow.
明天一早
Hurry up.
快点儿 就等你了
We can't let anyone sneaking in
这种歪门邪道进来的
get too comfortable.
就不能让他闲着
[The Fourth Station has gone.]
哥 这四所都没了
[What's he]
他小子凭什么
[still doing here?]
还能来我们这里啊
[Who knows? No shame.]
谁知道呢 脸皮厚呗
[Must have given out plenty of gifts.]
估计没少送礼吧
[Stop the chatter. Let's go drink.]
别废话 喝酒去
[I'm freezing.]
冻死我了
[Let's go.]
走
We're leaving.
走了
We're off.
快走 走了
[Take it easy on the road,]
那你们路上慢点儿
[Chief.]
所长
Take it slow.
你慢着点儿
Alright.
行
Head back.
回去吧 别送了
You've been drinking,
你们喝了酒了
Watch out for slippery roads.
这天也冷 小心路滑啊
Don't worry.
放心吧
Go back.
回吧
Chief,
所长
I have been confused all along.
我有个事一直没太明白
Don't you find it odd
你不觉得咱四所被撤
how our Station got shut down?
这事儿有点儿奇怪吗
I had someone look into it.
我托人打听了
Some stations need to be
市政府紧缩财政
cut down due to financial reasons.
确实要撤掉一批警察所
But we're not among them.
但四所没在那名单上
Then added later.
是后来加上去的
Later?
后来
When?
多后来
Right after we visited
就咱们去那个
that missing journalist's home.
失踪的记者家之后
Have you noticed
而且你发现了吗
that the people who went there
所长和队长没去
were later dismissed,
撤所之后就留职了
but those didn't
咱们去了的
were allowed stay on duty?
回来就撤职了
You do have a point.
好像是这么回事儿啊
That's not true!
是个屁呀是
Let me tell you,
告诉你们啊
there are rules about
这次改制人员去留
this restructuring.
都是有规定的
People rated
像我们所长还有队长
[as chief or captain,]
这个级别
[unless a major screw-up,]
没犯重大错误
[can remain in employment.]
就一律留用
[Drop your conspiracy theories.]
别疑神疑鬼的
Let's go.
都走了走了
Still, it feels strange to me.
反正我就觉得奇怪
Yuansheng...
小 小向这
is this your car?
你的车吧
Yes,
对
I got a vehicle from the garrison.
我跟驻地申请了用车
I can drive you back.
可以送你们回去
Nice, a ride back.
有车坐 敢情好
Weren't
所长
we supposed to leave together?
不是说好一起走的吗
When...
什么时候
Let's go.
走
Yuansheng,
远生
just drop Minmin off.
你把珉敏送回去就行
[Stop pulling me!]
你别拉我
I'll go with you.
我跟你们一起
Not good. We're gonna take a bath!
一起不了 我们洗澡去
I'll take you back then.
我送你回去吧
Thanks for the trouble.
那麻烦你了
No worries.
不客气
Still going to
你现在还每天
the police training every day?
都去女警训练班
I remember you
我记得你之前
graduated from there before.
就是女警训练班毕业的
But I barely
但是之前
learned anything last time.
学得稀里糊涂的
Felt like I understand nothing.
好像什么都没学会
I wanna go through it again properly.
我想重新再学一次
Willing to be back to the police force?
以后还打算接着当警察
Haven't thought that far yet.
还没想那么远
Right now,
现在就想
just wanna learn as much as I can.
什么都多学一点儿
Being at the Fourth Station
在四所待了一段时间
made me realize
我才发现
that I really don't know much.
其实自己什么都不会
Learning more now
现在多学习
will always be useful later.
以后总是能用得上的
Congratulations.
恭喜你啊
For what?
恭喜什么
[Before I left Shanghai,]
我离开上海前
you told me
你跟我说你想成为
that you wanna be someone useful.
一个有用的人
You're
恭喜你
one step closer
离自己的目标
to that goal.
更近了一步
You too.
你也是啊
Next time,
说不定下次再见面
I might be calling you Captain Hua Zhen.
我就要叫你华桢舰长了
Luo Minmin.
骆珉敏
at the train station that day,
离开前我在火车站
I called to tell you
给你打过电话
that we can write letters
我说我们可以写信
and the address...
我也告诉你我电雷
It's true I didn't write.
我确实没有给你写信
After you left,
你走之后
I went back to the training academy,
我就去了女警训练班
filled with classes, practical exercises,
每天都要上课实操练习
and so much
好多东西
that I've never met before.
都是以前没学过的
Like pistol shooting,
手枪射击
driving, etc.
开车
I have to invest much time.
不花时间根本学不会
And I need to
回家后
help out at my dad's photo shop
我还要帮爸爸
when I get home.
打理照相铺子
I don't make any money.
我光交学费不挣钱
My dad
家里光靠爸爸
can't manage alone.
一个人不行
I didn't have time on anything else.
我实在没有时间想别的
You must be busy too, right?
我猜你也一样吧
[Probably even more than me.]
你应该比我还要忙
What are you trying to say?
你想说什么
I'm doing well now.
我现在过得挺好的
Every day is full.
每天都很充实
Just let the holiday thing
假期的事情
be in the past.
过去就过去了吧
In over two months,
两个多月的时间
you've moved forward a lot.
你往前迈了一大步
Haven't you as well?
你不也是吗
We're both moving forward.
我们都在往前继续走
Although the Fourth Station has gone,
虽然四所没了
luckily we still see each other often.
好在大家经常见面
When we're at Dongbao's place,
在冬宝家的时候
everyone says
他们就老说
it would be great if you could be there too.
要是你也能在就好了
It's not easy to have a few
能有几个这样的朋友
good friends like that.
不容易
Are we good friends then?
我们现在算好朋友吗
Aren't we?
不算吗
I guess
我估计
you're the only
我这辈子也只能
influential friend
认识你这么一个
I'll ever have.
有权有势的朋友
If you think
要是你觉得
we're just ordinary friends,
只是普通朋友
I'm okay with that too.
我也接受
If you say so.
你说算就算吧
Excuse me,
你好
are you alright?
请问 您怎么了
Miss Luo,
骆警官
do you remember me?
还记得我吗
We met before
之前
at the police station.
我们在警察所见过面
Oh, right.
我想起来了
Mrs. Peng,
您是彭太太
you filed a report at the station before.
之前您来四所报过案
What's wrong?
怎么了
[Don't worry,]
您放心
[he used to be an officer there as well.]
他之前也是四所的警员
Mrs. Peng,
彭太太
are you feeling unwell?
您是不是哪儿不舒服
I have severe stomach pain.
我胃疼得厉害
Just came from the hospital.
刚从医院出来
This is my home.
这就是我家
How about
这样吧
coming inside with me?
您跟我一起进屋
No,
不了
I shouldn't.
就不进去了
I can't go in.
我不能进去
Earlier,
刚才
I didn't dare to knock on your door.
我就没敢去敲你们家门
[Prevent you from any trouble.]
怕给你们惹麻烦
Is something wrong?
是出什么事儿了吗
I really didn't know
我实在是不知道
who else to turn to.
该找谁帮忙了
I tried
之前
going to your station,
我去过四所找你们
but it's closed.
但是四所关门了
I escaped.
我是逃出来的
Someone is trying to catch me.
有人要抓我
Who
谁要抓你
I'd like to know that too.
我也想知道
Since my husband disappeared,
我丈夫失踪以后
I've been hiding in a boarding house.
我就一直躲在客栈里
[I can't stand the stomach pain.]
今天实在是胃疼得厉害
So I went to Guangci Hospital.
我就去了广慈医院
But I didn't stay there for long.
但是我也没敢久留
As I went out,
我刚从医院出来
a truck
就有一辆货车
was rushing to me.
冲出来要撞我
Fortunately, I dodged it.
还好我躲开了
Then I jumped into a tram.
我是跳上电车才逃脱的
The truck
那辆车
followed me around here.
一直追我到这附近
[Who were]
那那辆车上
[in that truck?]
都是些什么人
I don't know.
我不知道
Before my husband disappeared,
我丈夫失踪之前
it parked
那辆货车
around my house several times.
就好几次停在我家附近
No number plate.
也是没有挂牌的
But
只是当时
I didn't pay attention to it.
我根本没有在意
Does anyone else know
你住客栈的事儿
where you currently live?
还有其他人知道吗
I don't think so.
应该没有人知道吧
But I reckon
但是我在想
they probably
是不是因为
found me
我去过几次医院
in the hospital.
他们才找到我的
Is it related to
这件事
my husband's disappearance?
跟我丈夫失踪有关系吗
Get out of here.
先离开这儿
Who did this?
谁干的
Go get them.
给老子追
Mr. Xiang,
向警官
you can drive to a trail.
要不你把车开到小路
I'll carry
我从小路
Mrs. Peng back.
背着彭太太回去
They wouldn't
他们应该想不到
expect us to do this.
我会原路返回
I have another idea.
向警官 我还有个办法
What is it?
什么办法
I can wear Mrs. Peng's clothes
我穿上彭太太的衣服
to attract their attention.
把他们引开
Keep quiet.
你不要说话了
Show your papers, please.
请出示一下证件
Take care.
来
[I major in]
电雷学校二期
[navigation science]
航海科三班学员
[of the S.M.C.]
华桢
Is the patient your relative?
病人是你的亲属
Yes.
对
[How's about the medical expenses?]
费用怎么结算
All on my credit.
都记在我的名下
[OK.]
好
Your papers, sir.
先生 您的证件
Thank you.
谢谢
Let's go for Mrs. Peng.
去看看彭太太吧
We should go.
走吧
The doctor said
医生说彭太太
she's frightened
没什么大事儿
into a coma.
昏迷只是因为受了惊吓
She's too weak
过度虚弱
and needs rest.
安静休息就行
Would those guys break in?
那些人真的进不来吗
It's an affiliated hospital to the shipyard.
这是造船所的附属医院
All patients here are its employees.
来看病的都是内部职员
Guards
门口也有
are on duty 24/7.
二十四小时的警卫站岗
This is the safest place
这已经是我想到
I had ever thought.
最安全的地方了
Such
那
being the case,
彭太太没事
I should leave now.
我就走了
Where are you going so late?
你大晚上去哪儿
Home.
我回家了
Follow me.
跟我过来
Inpatients are not too many,
医院病人不多
This is available.
刚好还有多余的病房
I will apply for you to stay
我就申请让你在这儿
this night.
住一晚
Are you worried that it's dangerous
你是担心楼下车还在
for me to go back now?
我现在回去不安全
No. In case no one beside her
我是担心彭太太醒了
when Mrs. Peng wakes up.
没有人照顾
It sounds reasonable!
那倒也是
I should stay here.
我在这儿留着最合适
I have to go.
我先走了
Take care.
记得锁门
After she reported the case,
彭太太报案后
did you look into it?
你查过这个案子
Yes.
对
My colleagues and I
我带着四所的警员
went to her home
一起去过彭记者家门口
for investigation.
调查情况
Then,
不过
the captain told me
队长跟我说
to leave it alone.
叫我别管了
Are you saying Chen Hao?
陈浩让你别管了
He said he would investigate.
他说他会调查的
Then I haven't
四所撤了之后
paid any attention to this
他被调去十六铺分局
since he's
我也就没有打听过
transferred to Shiliupu.
这件事
Is something wrong?
怎么了
Nothing.
没事儿
Good night.
早点休息
Mom,
妈
is my brother at home?
哥哥在家吗
[No.]
他不在
[He went on a business trip to Shanghai.]
你哥哥去上海出公差了
Really?
他来上海了
When?
什么时候
[He should have arrived yesterday.]
昨天应该就到了
[Hasn't he contacted you?]
他没有联系你吗
I got it, mom.
好 没事儿了 妈
[A reporter surnamed Peng]
有一个姓彭的记者
[is missing.]
找不到了
[He is]
跟我一个好朋友
[my friend's relative.]
算是亲戚关系
Many are
现在不少人
looking for him.
都在到处找他
I heard the case
听说这件事情
was registered
是在你以前
in the station
待过的警察所
you served in before.
立的案
I'm entrusted to learn more.
所以托我问问
[How did you]
你是怎么发现
[find the truck?]
那辆货车的
[Since Mrs. Peng went to the police,]
自从彭太太来报案后
[I have been]
我就一直在暗中跟着她
[following her]
看看有没有人
[in secret.]
来找她麻烦
[Today,]
今天
[she went to Guangci Hospital.]
她又去广慈医院看胃病
[When coming out,]
从医院出来的时候
I spotted a truck without a number plate
我发现有辆无牌照货车
parking at the gate.
等在门口
I suspect that Feng Guangyun
我怀疑那辆货车
privately raised
是冯广云在外面
an action team
养的行动队
[with trucks]
之前我跟向远生
[as the main tool.]
查孟家凶杀案的时候
[I met a truck of the same type]
也遇到过一辆无牌货车
[when I investigated]
样式跟今晚的一样
the murder case
如果这真是冯广云
with Yuansheng.
在外面专门
If it's true,
下黑手的行动队
Peng's disappearance
那彭记者失踪
is definitely related to the truck.
肯定跟这辆车有关
On which road did it disappear?
车是开到哪条路消失的
Fuhua Road.
福华路
It disappeared
它拐了一个弯
after
我跟了上去
turning a corner.
车就不见了
I thought
我怀疑它开进
it drove into a yard.
附近的院子里
There's
我在路口
a gas station
看见一个加油站
at the intersection.
但当时已经关门了
It should
现在只能
be able to provide us
通过这个加油站
with some info
来打听附近
about trucks around there.
来加油的货车
OK.
好
I'm in charge of it.
加油站我来查
Hope we can find Peng
希望能通过这辆车
through the truck.
找到彭记者
I didn't find his name
我查了十六铺分局的
on the records
看守所
of Shiliupu's
也查了从分局
detention house and the prisoners
转去提篮桥监狱的犯人
transferred to Tilanqiao.
都没有彭记者
There's no interrogation record
现在除了一张逮捕令
except an arrest warrant.
没有任何的审讯记录
Is it possible that
有没有一种可能
Mr. Peng had been executed?
彭记者已经遇害了
I had thought of it.
我也想过
But based on
但是从
what happened tonight,
今天晚上的事情来看
we seem to still have a slim chance.
我们还有一线生机
They came to
他们之所以
Mrs. Peng
会去找彭太太
because
那是因为
they didn't get
没有从彭记者身上
what they want
找到他们想要的秘密
from Mr. Peng.
或者证据
In this case,
在这种情况下
Mr. Peng is still valuable
彭记者对他们来说
to them.
还是有价值的
In my opinion,
所以我觉得
he should be detained
应该不是灭口
in an unknown place
而是秘密关押
until they find
直到他们找到
what they want.
他们所想要的东西
Now we have to
现在当务之急
take Mrs. Peng to a safe place
是要把彭太太
as soon as possible.
接到安全的地方
Before, I followed Mr. Deng
我之前跟着邓先生
into Jiangnan Shipyard.
进过江南造船所
Guests can only stay
里面能留宿外人的
the guesthouse
除了招待所
or the affiliated hospital.
就是附属医院
The
对
guesthouse requires a letter.
招待所需要介绍信
Mrs. Peng
既然彭太太
is more likely to be arranged
会因为胃病去医院
in the hospital
那向远生
by Xiang Yuansheng
把她安顿在医院的
due to her stomach disease.
可能性就更大
Our men working
我会马上通过组织
for the Power Bureau
委托电力局的同志
go to the shipyard
去办这件事情
for maintenance
平日里每周三
every Wednesday.
都会去造船所
I'll request the organization
轮电工作所检修
to arrange someone
也就是后天
to rescue her during such period.
他就能把彭太太救出来
Mr. Deng gave me
邓先生之前
a technician certificate
给过我一张
of the Shipyard.
江南造船所的技工证
If your plan
如果刚才说的办法
didn't work,
行不通
I'd take her out.
就换我去
No, except we're
不到迫不得已
driven into a corner.
你不能出面
Though you're
虽然我从公董局
transferred,
把你弄到刑警科
Feng Guangyun
但是冯广云
doesn't trust you.
不可能信任你
You can't take risks.
你现在要避免冒险
What happened?
怎么回事儿
Mr. Feng,
冯哥
that woman fled into
那女人躲进了
Jiangnan Shipyard
江南造船所
with naval men guarded`.
门口有海军守着
We can't go in.
我们进不去了
Where?
躲哪儿
Jiangnan Shipyard.
江南造船所
She got in
她半路上了辆
a military jeep.
军用吉普车
Then
我们一直在后边跟着
we saw it
最后看见它
driving in the Shipyard.
开进了造船所
And allowed
海军警卫
in by the guards?
就让他们进去了
Yes.
是
Have we
冯哥
offended
我们是不是
the military?
得罪军方的人了
Did you see
吉普车上什么人
who were in the jeep?
你看见了吗
No.
没看清长相
Should be a man and a woman.
从远处看是一男一女
Did they see you?
他们也看见你们了
Maybe not.
隔得很远
We stayed afar.
应该没有看见
And
再说了
we don't have a number plate.
我们也没有挂车牌
They can't trace anything.
应该查不到的
Don't drive the truck
这两天没有我的通知
without my order.
别动车了
And stay away
那个女人的事儿
from the woman.
你也别管了
Why not
不是
ask
那咱不能
the police to arrest and charge her,
跟处理那个记者一样
just like what we did
先让警察把她抓起来
to the reporter?
然后再安个罪名
Who?
让谁
The police.
警察
You're employed
我养你们就是为了
to do dirty jobs.
干这些见不得光的事儿
Think twice
你办事儿的时候
before you do something.
要能稍微带点儿脑子
The woman
现在记者老婆
is already around us.
人就已经在这儿了
Sorry for that.
我错了冯哥
Absurd!
还警察
I have to
这事儿还得
deal with it myself.
我自己亲自来
Listen up.
大家都听一下
The accomplice to the
我的线人发现
warehouse murder was found
仓库凶杀案的从犯
hiding in Jiangnan Shipyard.
躲进了江南造船所
[Go there with me.]
跟我出趟任务
[Yes, sir.]
是
Chief,
科长
how about Chen Hao?
陈浩也去吗
Are you suggesting
怎么着啊
[leaving him]
留他一个人
[here to relax?]
在这儿自由自在啊
Be quick.
都利索点儿
Is the suspect
王警官
a man or a woman?
嫌疑人是男是女
How catch the criminal
不知道长什么样
knowing nothing?
怎么抓人
Don't talk nonsense.
要你去你就去
Close up!
哪儿这么多废话
Here you are.
姑娘拿好
[Why so many policemen here?]
怎么来了这么多警察呀
[Something must have happened.]
是啊 有热闹瞧了
Stop there.
什么事儿
The Criminal
我们是十六铺分局
Investigation Dept.
刑侦科的
requests a search
我们怀疑有一名疑犯
'cause a suspect
躲到造船所里
seems to be hiding inside.
需要进去搜查
Check the search warrant.
这是搜查令
What suspect?
什么疑犯
I can't tell you.
这个不方便透露
This is the restricted area.
这是海军重地
Before any search,
如果要进行搜捕
you must contact the Security Dept.
必须和警卫处进行交涉
Chief,
科长
he refused us.
海军重地 不让咱进
[What's wrong?]
怎么了
You go first.
你们先去
[OK.]
行 走吧
May I use the phone?
电话借用一下
Chen Hao.
陈浩
Sir.
到
You've been doing very well lately.
这段时间在分局辛苦了
So,
这样
I give you a chance
今天给你个机会
to talk with your old partner.
去跟你老搭档叙叙旧
I haven't seen him for long.
我跟他也好久没见了
Nothing to say.
没什么可聊
This is a great chance.
所以让你叙旧嘛
You're in a close relationship
你们之前在四所
with him before.
关系这么好
Tell him to ask the guard
你跟他说一声
to allow us in,
让他跟警卫说一下
'cause we don't have time
我们着急进去
to contact the Dept.
没时间跟警卫处交涉了
I know him well.
科长 他这人我了解
He won't do me the favor.
他不一定能给我这面子
I always think highly of you.
我一直都看好你
You've asked
之前你不是
about cases.
还问我案子吗
I know you wanna achieve results.
我知道你想加入刑警科
The time has come.
咱是不得做出点儿成绩
OK.
好
Stop.
站住
Second lieutenant.
少尉
Long time no see.
好久不见
I almost couldn't
穿上军装
recognize you in uniform.
差点儿没认出来
When did you come here?
什么时候回的上海
Just a few days.
刚来
Why are you here?
你来造船所
For a mission.
执行任务
So do I.
我也是
We're told just now
我们刚刚得到消息
that a fugitive is hiding here.
说一名逃犯进了造船所
We wanna go in for a search.
想进去看一看
The guard
警卫刚刚
has told you clearly.
也说得很清楚了
It's not a military control area.
造船所毕竟不是军队
Shouldn't be managed so strictly.
应该没那么严格吧
Would you kindly
能不能通融一下
make an exception for us?
不要通过警卫处
Not a military base,
虽然不是军队
but related to military secrets.
但造船所涉及军事机密
Moreover,
更何况这几天
we have a special mission here.
有特殊任务
Even a registration in the Dept.
就算跟警卫处报备
can't work.
也不可能放行
I was called over by Mr. Feng.
冯科长派我过来交涉的
Could you help me?
能不能通融一下
[Well,]
那我就把话
I'll make a detailed explanation
说得再明白一点
to help you respond better.
方便你回去交差
I come here
我来造船所
for a reception mission.
是为了执行接收任务的
During this period,
任务期间
it is impossible for the Shipyard
造船所不可能冒着
to allow unrelated policemen
泄露军事机密的风险
to enter
放几个
at the risk of leakage of secrets.
不相干的警察进来
So,
所以
you can only
在我们执行完任务
wait outside
离开之前
until the mission ends.
你们就只能在外面等着
Xiang Yuansheng
科长
has been promoted to second lieutenant.
向远生居然是少尉了
He said we couldn't defy their rules.
他说他们有他们的规矩
Let's go back.
收队
The organization said
白天接到组织的消息
that Tan Shiyuan
明天中午
will receive an honored guest
谭施远会在一品香
tomorrow noon.
接待贵客
The man
不排除
on the left may appear.
就是照片上第三个人
You have to
你要想办法
find a way to check it out.
前去调查一下
We can't see his face.
左边这个人没有正脸
His wrist is the point.
他唯一的特征就是手臂
I amplified
我专门去
the detail
把他手臂上这个细节
on the wrist.
放大了
It looks like
这个人手臂上的疤
the letter Y.
很像个英文字母的Y
I checked
我查过谭施远身边
Tan's social relations,
所有来往密切的人
but got nothing about this man.
实在查不到这个人
But I'm certain
但是我敢确定
that he's involved in Peng's disappearance.
他跟彭记者失踪案有关
Keep an eye on him when
所以你在冯广云身边
under Feng Guangyun.
要留心这个人
Got it.
记住了
How have you been lately?
最近在分局还好吗
Not bad.
还行
I didn't engage in espionage,
虽然没有做过地下工作
but I served in the police for five years.
但好歹当了五年的警察
I know what I should do.
警惕性还是有的
Have a sense of proportion.
得要有分寸
If Feng pushed you hard
如果冯广云
on purpose,
有意要针对你
you shouldn't bear it too much.
你也不能太隐忍
That's different from you before.
因为以你以前的性格
Otherwise,
如果太隐忍
he'd think you're up to something.
他会觉得你另有所图
No worries.
放心
I'll do Chen Hao's
我会扮演好陈浩
character setting well.
分寸我自己掌握
Do you remember how to say
还记得遇见的法语
"meet" in French?
怎么说吗
Rencontre.
遇见 遇见
Do you know
你知道这一次
why you're not
为什么上级
sent to pick up Mrs. Peng?
不安排你去接彭太太吗
Because you met Xiang Yuansheng,
因为你和向远生的遇见
the situation would be more complex.
会让事情变得更复杂
Take the pistol.
东西交到你手上
I hope you'll never pull the trigger.
希望你永远用不上
He must think
他现在肯定以为
I'm working for Feng Guangyun.
我在替冯广云做事情
Keep the Fourth Station and him
不管是四所还是他
as far as possible.
牵扯得越少越好
Who is eating
咱们谭副局长
with Mr. Tan?
是在跟什么长官吃饭
I have no idea
长官们的事情
who it is.
我哪里晓得
[I heard he's from Nanjing.]
听说好像是南京来的
Really?
这饭局这么高级的吗
[Attention!]
站好
[Two men in a group]
两人一组巡逻
[on patrol]
里里外外
[for each and every inch.]
每个角落都监察到
[Do it now.]
赶紧
Yes, sir.
是
[Come on.]
来来来
[Let's]
我们大家一起
[propose a toast to Mr. Hua.]
敬华秘书一杯
[Cheers.]
一起干杯
[To Mr. Hua.]
华秘书
[Mr. Hua]
华秘书可是
[is a busy man.]
可是大忙人啊
[Yes.]
是啊
[Let's drink up.]
干了 干
[You're afar from Nanjing.]
华秘书从南京来
[It's our great honor to meet you.]
舟车劳顿 辛苦了
[This is Xiang Yuansheng's]
这是向远生的哥哥
[elder brother.]
华秘书
[He came]
他是专程
[specifically from Nanjing.]
从南京赶过来的
[Nice to meet you.]
幸会 队长
[Mr. Hua.]
华先生
[Captain Chen,]
陈队长
[thanks for your kindness.]
谢谢你的好意
[I'm certain]
左边这个背影
[that he's]
我敢确定
[involved in]
他跟彭记者的
[Peng's disappearance.]
失踪案有关